Almas Baimagambetov

STATEMENT

I am an active researcher in the field of automated diagram generation. I teach a range of Computer Science modules to 1st, 2nd and 3rd year university students. I contribute to a number of open-source projects on GitHub. I run an educational YouTube channel covering game and software development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oct. 2017 - Present	Part-time Lecturer & Module Leader in Game Development $University\ of\ Brighton,\ UK$
Oct. 2015 - Oct. 2017	Hourly-Paid Lecturer in Programming and Game Design & Development University of Brighton, UK
June 2014 - Oct. 2016	English-Russian Interpreter (Zero-Hour Contract) $LLP\ AktubNIGRI,\ Kazakhstan$
Jan 2013 - Oct. 2016	In-house Programmer (Zero-Hour Contract) LLP AktubNIGRI, Kazakhstan

EDUCATION

July 2015 - Oct. 2018 (Expected)	PhD in Computer Science, University of Brighton, UK Thesis: Automated visualization of grouped networks using Euler diagrams and graphs keywords: set theory, graph theory, topology, computational geometry & graphics
Oct.2012 - July 2015	BSc Computer Science (Games), University of Brighton, UK Final year project: Analysis of software development issues in large scale games Project grade: 87% (A+), Degree: 1st Class Honours
Sept. 2011 - June 2012	Foundation Degree in IT, Bellerbys College, UK Grade: 94% (A+)

AWARDS

June 2018	Best Student Paper, Diagrams 2018 Conference	
Sept. 2015	International Research Scholarship (50% fee reduction) University of Brighton	
July 2015	Best Final Year Development Project (£250) The FDM Group Prize	
Nov. 2014	Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000) University of Brighton	
Nov. 2013	Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000) University of Brighton	
June 2012	2012 Top #1 Foundation Student, Bellerbys College	
May 2012 Best IT Student, Bellerbys College		
Research Talks		
June 2018	Generating Effective Euler Diagrams (10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams)	
May 2017	Novel Algorithm for Euler Diagram Generation (University of Brighton Internal Conference)	
March 2017	Data Visualization Workshop (Presenter at Data Visualization Brighton Meetup)	
Feb. 2017	An Inductive Approach to P-preserving Euler Diagram Generation (Visual Modelling Group Talk)	
June 2016	Grouped Networks and Associated Challenges (University of Brighton Internal Conference)	
May 2016	Euler Diagram Generation Techniques (Visual Modelling Group Talk)	

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **Baimagambetov, A.**, Howse, J., Stapleton, G. and Delaney, A. (2018) Generating Effective Euler Diagrams In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018. (Accepted for long paper).
- 2. **Baimagambetov, A.** (2018) Automated Visualization of Grouped Networks In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018. (Accepted for Graduate Symposium report).